claires.com 2018-03-10

# Privacy Policy | Claire's

We take privacy really seriously and work super hard to protect your personal details, take a look at what we do with your information and the choices you can make about how it’s collected and used…

  * Why we collect this information
  * What information we collect
  * Shopping
  * General Browsing
  * How we collect information
  * Use of Cookies
  * Our Cookies Policy
  * Use of web beacons, clear-GIFs, pixel tags and Javascript
  * Widgets and Server Logs
  * How we use the information we collect
  * Your choice about the information we collect
  * Privacy of children who visit the site
  * Information stored outside of the United Kingdom
  * Updating personal information
  * Links
  * Security
  * Questions / Changes in Policy

This privacy policy (the "Privacy Policy") applies to the claires.co.uk, m.claires.co.uk and claires.fr websites (however accessed and/or used, whether via personal computers, mobile devices or otherwise) and other interactive features or protocols that link to this privacy policy (including, without limitation, mobile sites, widgets & downloads) (collectively "The Site"), which is owned or controlled by Claires Accessories UK Ltd ("Claire’s”, "we", "us" or "our"). In addition, if Claire's also collects information at one of its retail stores, for example through Ear Piercing forms, this Privacy Policy will govern the use of that information and any of that information combined with information collected through The Site. 

The Site is owned and maintained by the company "Claires Accessories UK Ltd", a company registered at the Companies Registration Office of England and Wales under the registration number 3115118, with registered office at Unit 4, Bromford Gate, Bromford Lane, Birmingham, B24 8DL, United Kingdom and with VAT registration number GB927124727 (the "Company" or "Claires").

The site includes products (the "Goods" or the "Product(s)") of "Claire's Accessories UK Ltd". 

Wherever the terms "we," "our," or "us" are used in this privacy policy, we are referring to the practices of Claire's Accessories UK Ltd concerning the processing and collection of your information through the Site.

From time-to-time, the Company may provide you with communications about your order, or otherwise concerning information you might be interested in receiving, such as e-mails about loyalty rewards, sales, special items, and general marketing information about the Products and services. If you make a purchase via the Site you may be, and most probably are, providing your information to the Company to process orders. We inform you that any information you provide may be fully shared between the Company and a third party with whom the Company has entered in any kind of relationship following the terms established in the present Privacy Policy.

We are committed to taking reasonable steps toward protecting your privacy online and to managing your information responsibly.

This Privacy Policy is intended to notify you of our online privacy practices, the type of information that may be collected and stored, how the information is used; with whom the information may be shared; what choices are available to you regarding collection, use and distribution of the information; what kind of security procedures are in place to protect the loss, misuse or alteration of information under our control; and, who to contact with questions or concerns. 

This Privacy Policy does not apply to other websites to which we may link. We may post such links on the Site as a way of helping you locate related information and products easily. However, when linking to another website, you must review that website's privacy policy as other websites may not treat information collected online in the same manner as we do, and even though you contact them though the Site, the Site does not hold any responsibility on the treatment by this other websites your personal information.

By using the Site, or contacting call centre operations, you consent to the collection and use of information by us in accordance with this privacy policy. If we decide to change our privacy policy, we will post those changes on this page.

## WHY WE COLLECT INFORMATION

We collect personal information because it helps us deliver Products and services. For example, if you order a Product, we need to have information such as your billing address, age, Product choice, delivery information, and payment processing information. In addition, your personal information helps us communicate to you latest Products, special offers, and information and events about which you might like to hear.

We also collect your personal information to help us design and deliver Site operations, and to deliver targeted advertisements to you. We also may correlate your personal information obtained from you with information from other sources, which may help us to develop a more targeted user profile concerning you and/or your demographic information. For example, if you provide us with your personal information, we may cross-check that against information that might be otherwise available through other entities with whom we have business relationships in order to develop a more in-depth demographic profile of you. Similarly, we may process personal information to target specific items of interest to you. We know that everyone is busy, and nobody likes their email cluttered up with junk mail and as such we will only send you marketing messages if you choose to receive them from us. If you decide that you no longer want to receive our emails you can unsubscribe at any time by clicking and selecting 'Unsubscribe'.

## WHAT INFORMATION WE COLLECT

The following generally describes the type of information we may collect about you. 

Those who wish to communicate with us but do not wish to provide personally identifiable information online may contact us through the address or phone numbers provided on our website. However, you should note that if you contact us by phone, or if you contact us via postal mail, you may still be submitting personally identifiable information to us. For example, if you have a listed phone number without blocking, your phone number may appear to us when you call. Similarly, if you write to us and provide a name and return address, we will gather that information in order to communicate with you, and we may use the information in accordance with this privacy policy.

## SHOPPING

When you shop on the Site, we will collect the information necessary to complete your order, such as your name, e-mail address, shipping address, payment information (including credit card number and/or debit card number) and billing address. 

You may also choose to provide us with your gender and birth date, as well as other information that you might submit.

If you create an account, we will collect information about your purchases and payment methods, as well as the shipping addresses that you add to your address book, in order to make future shopping experiences faster and more convenient. We will use this information to process your transaction and despatch your order. Any data that is necessary to process your order is mandatory, the consequence of the refusal to provide it is that we will not process said order, on the other hand any information that is not necessary to process your order is not mandatory and the refusal to provide it has no consequence on the processing of your order.

## GENERAL BROWSING

We do not automatically collect your home address, email address, telephone number, and product preferences unless you voluntarily input this information, such as during a registration or ordering process, or when you submit questions or comments, request information, or participate in online surveys, contests, promotions or other activities. 

If you do not want us to collect and process and use your personal data other than the one necessary to fulfil the contractual obligations, please abstain yourself from filling this fields in any of the above.

Even if you do not submit personal information through the Site, we gather navigational information about where visitors go on the Site and information about the technical efficiencies of the Site and services (i.e., time to connect to the website, time to download pages, etc.). This information allows us to see which areas of the Site are most visited and helps us better understand the user experience. This helps us improve quality by recognising and delivering more of the features, areas, and services our visitors prefer. In this process of gathering information, we may collect for example, domain type, browser type and version, service provider and IP address, referring/exit pages, operating system, date/time stamp, and click-stream data). We may also create and use electronic records to compile statistics about how our visitors collectively interact with the Site.

## HOW WE COLLECT INFORMATION

We collect information in three primary ways:

1\. You give us information: We collect information from you when you purchase a service from us or when you interact with us about a Product or service we offer or provide. For example, you provide us when you order a Product or establish an account with us. 

2\. We collect information automatically: We automatically collect certain types of information when you visit the Site or use products and services. For example, we automatically collect various types of technical information when you use the Site as otherwise described in this privacy policy.

3\. We collect information from other sources: We may obtain information about you from outside sources. For example, we may obtain commercially available information about you from third parties, such as demographic information for advertising and marketing purposes. We may also receive information from third-parties who provide third-party tracking services through web-beacons as otherwise discussed in this privacy policy.

## Facebook and Other Third Party Connections. 

You can connect your Claire's account to your accounts on third party services like Facebook, in which case we may collect, use, disclose, transfer and store/retain information relating to your account with such third party services in accordance with this Privacy Policy. For example, if you connect with Facebook, we store your Facebook id, first name, last name, email, location, friends list and profile picture and use them to connect with your Facebook account to provide certain functionality on the Services, like recommending events that your Facebook friends are interested in and sharing the events you are interested in, or attending, with certain groups of people like your Facebook friends. 

## USE OF COOKIES

Cookies are bits of electronic information that a website may transfer to a visitor's computer to identify specific information about the visitor's visits to a website. The Site uses a browser feature known as a cookie, which assigns a unique identification to your computer. Cookies are typically stored on your computer's hard drive and are used to help track clicks as you go through the pages within the Site. 

Our cookies do not contain any sensitive information, such as your name, address or payment details.

We may also use cookies to tell us whether you have previously visited the Site. We also use cookies which may be set by third-parties with whom we have entered into agreements which may enable us to obtain other information about you as may be available from those third-parties, such as demographic data about you. You can set your browser not to accept cookies or to notify you when you are sent a cookie, giving you the opportunity to decide whether or not to accept it. You may also use commonly available tools in your browser to remove cookies which may have been placed onto your computer. If you want to delete any cookies that are already on your computer, please refer to the instructions for your file management software to locate the file or directory that store cookies. Alternatively you may wish to visit [www.aboutcookies.org](https://www.claires.co.uk/privacy/content/www.aboutcookies.org) which contains comprehensive information on how to manage cookies on a wide variety of browsers. However, please note that if you disable the use of cookies on your computer, some functionality of our site will not work you will not be able to shop on our Site, only browse. We will not use FLASH cookies, unless you are specifically notified that we intend to use them for a specific service, and you are given the opportunity to opt-out from receiving such cookies. FLASH cookies are cookies that are placed on your computer that are not removed through normal browser management tools, but the developer of the FLASH programming language currently has an on-line management tool to allow you to remove these FLASH cookies.

## OUR COOKIES POLICY

Please find below the list of cookies that we use:

Cookie Name | Description | Session or Persistent? | Expiry Time (if persistent) | Exempt?  
---|---|---|---|---  
JSESSIONID | Unique user session id - used directly by FCP to handle things such as basket management | Session |   | Y  
K-JSESSIONID-gdncaoo | These cookies are used to identify linked requests from a browser to ensure that the shopping cart works. | Session |   | Y  
X-Mapping-gbooldlg | These cookies are used to identify linked requests from a browser to ensure that the shopping cart works. | Session |   | Y  
country_iso | ISO code of the country setting of the browser | Persistent | 60 Days | N  
currency_iso | ISO of the currency code for the country | Persistent | 60 Days | N  
nextPreviousIds | Product IDs of the previous and next products if next previous functionality is used on product details screen |   |   | N  
view_format | The number of columns of products shown on the listings page |   |   | N  
lastCategory | last browsed category, used for breadcrumbs (may be superseded by fcp_last_category) | Persistent | 31 Days | N  
lastSuccessfulCategory |   | Persistent | 31 Days | N  
fcp_last_category | last browsed category, used for breadcrumbs | Persistent | 31 Days | N  
fcp_shopping_basket | Retains the customer's shopping basket contents between sessions. (See Basket Retention for more information about this one) | Persistent | Set as BASKET_COOKIE_MAX_AGE in seconds | N  
currentLAT | Used by the store finder when using ‘autofind’ to store current Latitude | Persistent | 7 Days | Y  
currentLNG | Used by the store finder when using ‘autofind’ to store current Longitude | Persistent | 7 Days | Y  
_qPageNum_claires | Used to store how many pages have been visited | Session |  | N  
Cookie Name | Description  
---|---  
FCP_MOBILE_LAST_CATEGORY | The last category that the customer looked at. Used in site navigation, for the 'Next' and 'Previous' buttons.  
FCP_MOBILE_LAST_SEARCH | The last on-site search the customer did.  
FCP_MOBILE_PRODUCT_IDS | Present but not used?  
_qPageNum_claires | Used to store how many pages have been visited  
Cookie Name | Party Using It  
---|---  
ARPTH | Bazaar voice  
BIGipServerprod-c5c-prr-http | Bazaar voice  
prr-sip | Bazaar voice  
goto | Bazaar voice  
qa-sip | Bazaar voice  
__utma | Google Analytics  
__utmb | Google Analytics  
__utmc | Google Analytics  
__utmz | Google Analytics  
PREF | Google Analytics  
Apis.google.com | Google Analytics  
_qPageNum_claires_mobile | Used to store how many pages have been visited  
_qsst | Qubit  
_qsst_s | Qubit  
_qst | Qubit  
_qubitTracker | Qubit  
Com.silverpop.iMA.page_visit | Silverpop  
Com.silverpop.IMA.session | Silverpop  
Com.silverpop.iMAWebCookie | Silverpop  
Sli_basket_count | SLI count items in basket  
Sli_currency_iso | Used by sli to detect currency iso  
Sli_fcp_shopping_basket | Used by sli to store current basket  
Uid | SLI  
SLI1_59187953 | SLI  
Ve interactive(id) | Used by VE interactive   
S7.addthis.com | Used by add this for social widgets  
Mobile_app | Used to detect if user if accessed the mobile site via app  
Mt.y |   
Monetate | Monetate (vary from experience to experience)  
  
## USE OF WEB BEACONS, CLEAR-GIFS, PIXEL TAGS AND JAVASCRIPT

We also use "pixel tags" (also called "action pixels," "web beacons" or "clear gifs") and/or JavaScript plug-ins, placed on our website and in our emails to you. 

These web beacons and plug-ins are small graphic images (typically that you cannot see) or code on a website or in an email message which are used for such things as recording web pages and advertisements clicked-on by a user, or for tracking the performance of email marketing campaigns. These devices help us analyse our customers' online behaviour and measure the effectiveness of the Site and advertising. We also work with third-party service providers that help us track, collect, and analyse this information. Third-party entities with whom we have agreements may place these devices on the website and/or in e-mails to use information obtained from them such as pages viewed, items purchased, e-mails opened and items upon which you may click in e-mails. These third-party providers may also place cookies onto your computer. Those third-party cookies may enable us to obtain aggregate demographic information and user statistics about you and your preferences from these third-party sources as well as our information we have about you.

## WIDGETS AND SERVER LOGS

A "widget" is generally an application that can be embedded in a web page. Widgets can provide real-time information to the page. Widgets are often provided by third-parties and we may provide widgets on the Site. Widgets may enable the third-parties that provide them to collect data about users visiting the Site. We may also obtain information shared with us through the providers of these widgets. 

A web "server log" is a record of activity created by a computer that delivers certain web pages to your browser. Certain activities that you perform on the Site may record information in server logs, such as if you enter a search term into a search box located on the Site. The server log may record the search term, or the link you clicked on to bring you to the Site. The server log may also record information about your browser, such as you IP address and the cookies set on your browser.

## SEARCH QUERIES ON OUR WEBSITE

We may provide you with options to search for information on the Site. If you enter information in a search query box, we may store that information and we may aggregate that information with other information we may have about the browser and/or IP address from which the search query originated.

## HOW WE USE THE INFORMATION WE COLLECT

We use the information we collect in a variety of ways. Generally, using all of the above mentioned, and similar type tools, we may collect, aggregate, and use information from or about you such as data about the type of browser and operating system used, which web pages you view, the time and duration or you visits to our Site, the search queries you may use on the Site, whether you clicked on any advertisements, whether you have clicked on any links in any e-mails sent from us, or third-parties on our behalf, whether you have chosen to opt-out of certain services or information sharing, and whether you have viewed or ordered certain products or services. 

We use the information we collect internally in our business for many business purposes, such as to: (i) provide the products or services you may order, including processing orders, return and third party payment providers; (ii) analyse trends and conduct research about improving our products and services; (iii) provide support and respond to questions from customers and visitors; (iv) improve the Site, products or services; (v) learn about customers' needs; (vi) contact consumers for research, informational, and marketing purposes, including customising our product recommendations to you based upon your information and purchases; (vii) track traffic patterns and site usage; (viii) enable online ordering and provide customer service with respect to such orders; (ix) correlate information with other commercially available information to identify demographics and preferences to assist us in our marketing efforts; (x) provide specific relevant marketing, promotional, or other information to you; (xi) address information security and/or privacy practices control, network functioning, engineering, and troubleshooting issues; (xii) investigate claims and/or legal actions, violations of Terms of Use, and compliance with relevant applicable laws and legal process; (xiii) comply with law, or based on our good faith belief that it is necessary to conform or comply with the law, or otherwise to disclose information to the agencies concerned to: prevent fraud, to reduce credit risks, to cooperate with police and other governmental authorities, or to protect the rights, property or safety of visitors to the website or the public.

We may also share personally identifiable information and non-personally identifiable information externally with other third-party service providers, which might include, but is not necessarily limited to the companies who handle our order despatch service, payment provider and our delivery company, business entities that provide e-mail address management and communication contact services, network equipment and application management providers and hosting entities, credit and debit card payment gateways and processors and the issuing and acquiring banks involved in the funds settlement procedures necessary to charge your cards or financial accounts, entities which obtain information such as demographic information which might be aggregated with information we have about you, judicial, administrative and/or legal or financial accounting providers in the event that information must be reviewed or released in response to civil and/or criminal investigations, claims, lawsuits, or if we are subject to judicial or administrative process (such as a subpoena) to release your information or to prosecute or defend legal actions, and other service providers which may be involved in the other types of services and activities otherwise discussed in this privacy policy. In the cases where it is required by data protection legislation We will enter into written agreements with these third-parties, to place contractual restrictions on these third-parties from further transmitting your personal data and the treatment of said data outside of the uses and processing necessary to fulfil their contracts with us. We will only provide these third parties with the information which they need to carry out their jobs. We may also use your personally identifiable information to contact you in ways other than e-mail or regular mail, such as via telephone contact and/or mobile messaging and texts to your mobile phone through SMS. 

Some elements on the Site, such as any sponsored links advertising, are supplied to us by third parties under contract. We may supply some of the information we collect from you to those third parties so that they can provide those elements for display. We may share the following information with such third parties: (a) your Internet Protocol (IP) address; (b) the address of the last URL you visited prior to clicking through to the Site; (c) your browser and platform type; (d) your browser language; (e) the data in any undeleted cookies that your browser previously accepted from us; and (f) the search queries or word look-ups you submit.

## YOUR CHOICES ABOUT THE INFORMATION WE COLLECT

If you do not consent to the way in which we may use your personal information, please do not submit any personal information to us.

If you do not wish to receive e-mails about special offers, new fashion trends, contests and other promotions from us click the unsubscribe link located in our e-mails. 

If you do not wish for us to share your personal information for any promotional or marketing purposes, please contact us and inform us of your wishes. Please provide enough information for us to determine the nature of your request.

## PRIVACY OF CHILDREN WHO VISIT THE WEBSITE

We recognise the importance of children's safety and privacy. We do not request, or knowingly collect, any personally identifiable information from children under the age of 12.

## INFORMATION STORED OUTSIDE OF THE UNITED KINGDOM

When visiting the Site your connection will be through and to servers located in the United Kingdom. All information you receive from us will be created on servers located in the United Kingdom, and all information you provide will be maintained on web servers and systems located in the United Kingdom. The data protection laws in the United Kingdom might not be the same as the laws in other countries. By using the Site and/or submitting information to us, you specifically consent to the transfer of your information to the United Kingdom to the facilities and servers we use, and to those with whom we may share your information.

## UPDATING PERSONAL INFORMATION

We prefer to keep your personal information accurate and up-to-date. If you have a registered account with us would like to change your contact information, please visit ‘My Account' section and update your personal information details.

## LINKS

For your convenience, the Site may contain links to other websites. We are not responsible for the privacy practices, advertising, products, or the content of such other websites. None of the links should be deemed to imply that we endorse or have any affiliation with the links.

## SECURITY

We believe in providing a safe and secure experience for all of our online visitors. To that end we have implemented security measures to protect the information collected from you. 

Please note that no data transmitted over the Internet or stored and utilised for business purposes can be guaranteed to be completely secure. No security measures are perfect or impenetrable. We cannot guarantee that only authorised persons will view your information. We cannot ensure that information you share on the Site will not become publicly available. You can reduce these risks by using common sense security practices such as choosing a strong password, using different passwords for different services, and using up to date antivirus software.

## QUESTIONS / CHANGES IN POLICY

If you have questions or concerns with respect to our privacy policy, please contact us at enquiries@claires.co.uk. We may elect to change or amend our privacy policy; in such event, we will post the policy changes in our privacy policy on the Site.
